The man who made 007 a household number.
Diamonds Are Forever is a action, thriller film directed by Guy Hamilton.
Diamonds are stolen only to be sold again in the international market.
James Bond infiltrates a smuggling mission to find out who's guilty.
The mission takes him to Las Vegas where Bond meets his archenemy Blofeld.
James Bond, played by Sean Connery.
Tiffany Case, played by Jill St. John.
Ernst Stavro Blofeld, played by Charles Gray.
Plenty O'Toole, played by Lana Wood.
Willard Whyte, played by Jimmy Dean.
Albert R. Saxby, played by Bruce Cabot.
Diamonds Are Forever is a 1971 spy film and the seventh film in
the James Bond series produced by Eon Productions.
It is the sixth and final Eon film to star Sean Connery, who returned to the role as the fictional MI6 agent
James Bond, having declined to reprise the role in On Her Majesty's Secret Service (1969).
The film is based on Ian Fleming's 1956 novel and is the second
of four Bond films directed by Guy Hamilton.
The story has Bond impersonating a diamond smuggler to infiltrate a smuggling ring and uncovering a plot by
his old enemy Ernst Stavro Blofeld to use the diamonds to build a space-based laser weapon.
Bond sets out to stop the smuggling but discovers he must defeat Blofeld before he destroys
Washington, D.C., in his plan to blackmail the world with nuclear supremacy.
After George Lazenby left the series, the producers Harry Saltzman and Albert R.
Broccoli tested other actors, but the studio United Artists wanted Connery back,
paying a then-record US$1.25 million salary for him to return.
The producers were inspired by Goldfinger; as with that film, Hamilton was
hired to direct, and Shirley Bassey performed the title song.
Locations included Las Vegas, California, and Amsterdam.
Diamonds Are Forever was a commercial success and
received positive reviews upon release.
It was nominated for the Academy Award for Best Sound.
Diamonds Are Forever was followed by Live and Let Die in 1973,
with Roger Moore succeeding Connery as Bond.
The film explores themes of smuggling (contraband), fight,
amsterdam, netherlands, spy, secret organization.
The tone is intense.